welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
welcome to the stove I'm Peter Lindbergh
the steward of the stoah still a place
for us to cohere and dialogue but what
matters most at the knife's edge of this
moment and today we have the human
systems team joining us
Joey tlemen and just Watson Miller for
those of you don't know who are what the
human systems is it's a research network
for innovation in human systems and they
look at human systems new human systems
which better support participants agency
and life meanings and I took the human
systems course and it was really awesome
Joe and the team have done an excellent
job they're kind of giving the download
of their their system and so Joe texted
me he sent me a voicemail says dude I
don't know if he said dude but I just
that's my memory is this dude I got this
idea a social design Club it's a club of
people come in with your social designs
and then we kind of like test them
stress test them talk about them and
then all that type of stuff so I'm like
Joe whatever you want Joe gets and so uh
we started this and then so this is
gonna be a weekly or the ideas gonna be
a weekly online event where we someone
presents a social design system and then
they gets their feedback and I don't
know how today's gonna go so I'm going
to stop talking and I'm gonna take in
Jess and Joe in to introduce today's
session all right cool thank you so much
Peter and thanks for answering we had
voicemails with a yes so first of all
welcome everybody it's really exciting
to see so many people who are excited
about being part of social design Club
for the inaugural session just to give
you guys a a sense of what we're hoping
for here um the social design or least
the way that I think about social design
all the people think about social design
is kind of it's our own distinct field
is different from UX design or graphic
design or other aspects of design in
that it's really dealing with the
relationships between people and the
relationships between communi
and how the design you create shapes
those and the hope is that we can kind
of create a community of practice here
where we can really improve our own
designs and our own kind of skills and
thinking about design both through the
human systems lens with the frameworks
that human systems offers but also just
with people's own desire knowledge so
this is the first very first one and
we're very lucky to have Malcom ocean
here as our guest presenter we're hoping
to do a lot you know a lot more of these
and if you have a design that you're
interested in getting feedback on or
presenting in front of the social design
Club then we would love you to contact
us with with that because we want to
create a really thriving feedback and
ideas and critique kind of community
here so Malcolm ocean I introduced him
briefly I've known him for several years
and he's probably the person who I spent
the most time talking to in proportion
to how much time I've spent talking to a
new person we have collaborated on a lot
of things over the internet and he has
built for the last several years a
system called compass which is a
productivity system that's aiming on
aiming at helping you focus on what
matters to you and your in your goals
are in every everyday and so what we're
gonna do is he's going to quickly
present a bit about accomplice and then
a feature that he's working on or
workshopping um and then we're going to
get a chance to really dive into that
into some breakout rooms and give him
some ideas and thoughts and everything
and some feedback so I don't know
Jonathas anything you want to add before
we jump in with Malcolm yeah I'll just
say that um I think this is a really
important community of practice to build
and I'm a little embarrassed that I
wasn't part of building something like
this earlier because I've been
complaining about social networks social
apps have started like nonprofits that
are about complaining about social
networks
more recently complaining about you know
our systems for voting this the last
weeks policing you know we have really
bad social designs that are causing all
sorts of problems at many different
levels of society and yet there's not
very much of a community that's focused
on getting better at this and I think we
really need it right now and so that's
that's super exciting for me too like I
think this this this group could become
a very powerful thing so I guess we can
kick off with Malcolm he's just going to
explain a little bit about compass and
then afterwards we're gonna jump into a
QA and so if you have questions that
come up either while he's speaking or
while we're asking some questions then
pop them in the chat and we will we'll
take those questions yeah Malcolm you
want to unmute yourself
yeah hey can everybody hear me cool
alright so um so yeah I'm Malcolm ocean
I created a system a number of years ago
called com+ and I'll give you kind of a
brief overview demo of kind of the
system as a whole and and then I'll talk
about a feature that I I started working
on a few years ago and never launched
and I was thinking it would be a cool
thing to present at social design Club
so let's see sure screen oh I need
screen sharing abilities so yeah so so
basically accomplice kind of looks a lot
like a to-do list app but it's kind of
its kind of inside out compared to an
ordinary to-do list app but most to-do
list apps are like dumped in all of your
things organize them that kind of thing
com+ instead starts with what am I
actually trying to achieve in the world
and then each day you kind of focus on
that and so so I'll just sort of show
you the kind of the basic structure of
the UI you have a list of kind of active
goals that you're working on and and
there's at most ten active goals at any
given time you know I also have a huge
list of you know previous goals that I
used to have and like you know completed
goals and that kind of thing but you
have this list of active goals and what
I'm talking about a goal here it's like
I'm not talking about necessarily a
SMART goal you know SMA or T where you
have like metrics and targets and you
know precise deadlines and all of that
it's really more like you're why like
why am i doing what I'm doing what what
purpose am i moving towards personally
and so then the main page accomplice is
the today page where oh my that's
I just made some changes just before
this and so I'm just gonna roll back to
before those changes and that'll be fine
we're doing a live folks all right so so
anyway um so oh that's even weirder
okay well this version of the page
loaded fine so anyway we're just gonna
roll with that um so basically um you
have this list of kind of like what
you're working on for the day with your
goals kind of down here and you can see
how each of the items in this list is
colorized by the goal that it's oriented
towards right so you know I've got my I
was preparing for this event and that
was you know primarily under my design
goal so I have you know the so it's sort
of showing up in the kind of kind of
indigo blue of the design goal so I'm
going to check that off because I've you
know I've done my prep at this point and
now I'm I'm presenting and it's really
kombis is much more orient around
workflows then a lot of sort of to-do
list manager apps so it's like you go
into next action mode and then it's just
like well here's just slow but the one
thing I'm doing right now and then so
after setting your intentions for the
day you know you do things you have a
Pomodoro timer at the end of the day you
submit your outcomes and you reflect on
like how how is what I did towards each
of these goals how does that connect
with the goal um you know what was I in
touch with the goal was I out of touch
et cetera and there's a few different
versions of questions here that's
actually something I'll say I've been
designing but not what we're going to
talk about today so then of course you
have a history you know you can look
back over what you've what you've done
in the course of you know the past days
and weeks and then there's also kind of
reviews where you can reflect on you
know here's how the whole week went you
know and you ask yourself certain
questions so that's kind of a high-level
overview of the app itself and so a
couple of years ago I started thinking
well okay so it's like I've got my
person
goals but how do I want to relate to the
idea that like some of my goals are just
about my own life but other goals that I
have are about changing things you know
in the world so like you know maybe I
have a goal that's about you know you
know the environment or maybe I have a
goal that's about helping people in the
world be better at a particular skill or
something like that well that's actually
something that multiple people are
trying to achieve like I'm not the only
one trying to care for the environment
I'm not the only person trying to you
know reduce the chances of there being
global catastrophic risks you know there
are a lot of people out there right now
who in many different ways are trying to
mitigate the impacts of kovat right so
so I was when I created the the shared
purposes feature and the basic idea with
the shared purposes feature is you have
some something out there that multiple
people care about and these are mostly
just some examples I whipped up a while
ago um but if we'll just take this one
as an example so so basically you know
there's multiple people who have been
talking about metasomatism mehta
rationality or fluid mode or so on and
so this page then highlights kind of you
know there's this shared purpose that
people have of trying to convey to
people how would we operate in fluid
mode and so I can point this design goal
that I have towards that and then it
sort of shows you know here's here's
what I'm working on
you know today for instance and and this
box right here really think I'm maybe
going like a little fast or something so
I was really trying like I want to take
a step back and just say like the image
I had in mind when I was thinking about
this was almost like somebody like kind
of plants a flag around an idea and says
like hey this thing is important like
you know what if we focused on this and
other people recognized like hey I'm
also sort of focused on this so there's
a kind of like coming into connection
with people
who are already with people who are also
oriented towards some shared purpose and
my thinking with this was you know
there's a lot of you know productivity
apps and whatnot that are like designed
for like teams to coordinate towards
like shared it like you know towards
their company mission or that kind of
thing but a lot of them have implicitly
a kind of top-down this there's a the
the thing in the middle is we're a
company and and you know somebody's
making decisions about what needs to be
done and then we're kind of all doing it
um and I said what does it look like to
just like thinking about maybe Donella
Meadows leverage points and the leverage
point that like information flow is I
think number five it's like what
difference does it make to see other
people working on projects that are
trying to move the same needles in the
world as you like how can that be both
motivating or inspiring or create the
context where people might come into
relationship with each other and and
possibly collaborate on different
projects that that might be related
there or be able to share other
information like oh you're working on
this well check out this article that
might help you out so those are the
kinds of like interactions that I was
imagining happening from this I don't
think that the feature is at all at this
point sort of capable of creating most
of those interactions aside from just
seeing other people working on the thing
together and I'll show you what it looks
like
when you go to you click a button point
point a goal towards this purpose so I'm
gonna say actually that you know I have
a goal called system's thinking which is
mostly about learning systems thinking
but also about modeling systems and so
forth and I'm gonna say yeah this goal
actually is um it's quite relevant to
you know metasomatism curriculum because
systems thinking seems like and fairly
established discipline resonance with
meta systematicity and this is kind of
like a description of like how how is
systems thinking related to metasomatism
so you get to kind of write in there
something that links your goal with this
larger purpose and then what's cool is
depending on your sense of like privacy
of the goal you can actually click each
of these items so this this line here is
the description of my systems-thinking
goal if that contained like private
information I could hide that so it
doesn't actually get shared as part of
this purpose or I could say actually I
don't want people to see what I'm
working on I just want them to see that
I'm connected with this purpose that
what I'm working on contains
confidential information but they can
see that I'm working on so then I could
like I could I could hide these by
clicking on them it also might be that
under some circumstances that it makes
sense to you know edit the name of the
goal because the goal might might be
named for me and I might want a
different name for other people to see
in relation to that so I do all of those
and then I just hit save and now Systems
thinking is kind of added to this pile
of goals that are all pointed at the
meta systematicity curriculum that is
basically what exists so far but I think
in the context of the social design Club
it also makes sense to show you the
settings page to give you just a little
bit of a sense of how I've been thinking
if I go back um which is basically
currently this you know just sort of a
name and a description and so forth and
then there is visibility so is this you
know listed and discoverable or is it
you know unlisted like but you can find
it via a URL or private kind of pretty
typical three categories that YouTube
has as well and then there's also like
joint ability has either anybody or
invite-only or requests as in like this
purpose is like kind of a is kind of my
project right like so I'm not like you
can't just say hey I'm also working on
this project with you but you can say
hey I'd like to work on this project
with you and so that way there can be
kind of more of a membrane around who's
working on a particular purpose so
that's the shared purposes thing that's
kind of all that exists so far I think
it needs a little bit more in order for
to be able be able to really be the
thing that it wants to be and that's why
I didn't take off when I try presenting
it to a group of effective altruists
back in 2017
yeah but I think I think it has a
powerful chance to potentially be a cool
thing at the present you know even just
like related to like Cova door related
to you know the kinds of shared projects
that people seem in some ways more
oriented to under the with the whole
meta-crisis and everything so yeah so I
would invite people at this point to
notice things that you are curious about
or maybe didn't want to learn more about
if there's anything in this that you
kind of want to what would like mountain
to kind of explain a bit more and pop
those questions in the chat and Joe I
don't know if you have any questions you
want to start off with yeah I think it's
a beautiful it's a beautiful idea I
remember talking this Justin Rosenstein
the one of the founders of asana once
told me that this was kind of like his
big dream goal of asana was to D
aggregate the projects and goals and let
people form cross cross organization
goals like this but I guess he he hasn't
gotten around to it yet yeah he made
this thing called one project or
something that was trying to frame all
of what humanity was doing is one giant
project and I really liked that frame I
saw talk that he gave on that at Burning
Man and I think I saw that talk actually
just like a week or two after I've been
designing this so it's kind of a
convergent convergent thing cool yeah
I'll definitely send him the link to
this recording so I'm interested in a so
when I look at at this I think about
different kinds of collaboration values
towards these kinds of beautiful meta
goals that that I have one of them is
that I like to encourage people to be
like ambitious to reach for things try
it ways to help out on a scale that they
might not you know think about before so
discoverability of these shared purposes
is kind of like a relevant there right
how would I start to become part of a
shared purpose that I that I didn't know
about before another thing is about
getting real I think a lot of people
isolate themselves and work alone on on
their project like they have you know
their little
I don't know idea about reinventing
group process or something but they
don't work with other people because
that they're not really willing to do
the kind of hard work of making things
concrete that would be required to
actually coordinate in a group and so I
wonder about what kinds of design
features would actually be necessary to
support these kinds of things I don't
know if you have anything to say that
that's quite yeah yeah um I mean it's
one of those things that has a bit of
like a kind of chicken acting quality to
it it's like I I love to imagine what
this page would look like if if like
this feature was being used by thousands
of people I mean I think one thing is
that would become unwieldy in its
current form like you need a search
feature you need a filter feature and
you need like you know stuff like that
right so there's that but leaving that
aside it's like what what kinds of
things would we be seeing here and what
kind of um I've been thinking recently
so I keep I keep trying out sticking new
words in front of design and seeing what
happens and the main one I've been doing
lately is metaphor design and that's
been a super powerful intuition pump for
me like really great um a different
thing I've been thinking about is like
something like situation design so it's
like when somebody is looking at this
list what situation are they in you know
one metaphor that we might use for that
is like a university club's fair like
you know during the first week of
university there's a bunch of clubs
right and they're kind of recruiting
right so like and to some extent you
know they're just recruiting random
people but to also some extent you know
the a cappella club wants singers right
they want people who want to sing
right so there's a kind of like they're
not just trying to recruit anybody
they're trying to recruit you know
people who already have a resonance with
that so it's like you can think of this
as kind of like a club sphere or you
could think of it as kind of like a
conference like ei global where a bunch
of people come together and they say you
know I'm working on this project and I
think it's really important and here's
what I'm doing about it and somebody
else says I'm working on this project
and I think it's really important here's
what I'm doing about it and you know
other people who aren't actively working
on projects kind of go to these talks
and find out like why why these things
are important so even just saying that
right now it's like I hadn't thought
about in advance but saying that right
now it gets me thinking about like oh
the you know we're in here might people
write about like why they think this
thing is important for instance right
like that's that's a thing that could be
added right and so it's like okay you
know there could be like there could be
both like how does this how does this
particular goal of mine relate to this
and there's one thing I really like
about this which is that you can't join
you don't join a purpose as yourself you
join it with one of your goals so
there's no there's no way to just be in
the fan club of a purpose like there's
no way to just be like yeah I care about
that you have to say I'm working on that
with this goal like and that's something
that I find really delightful like
there's there's no like you know there
are things I care about collect like
globally but I don't have any particular
goals that I'm working on towards them
and it's like okay you know and maybe
there could be another relationship
that's something like you know fan or
subscribe or something like that where
it's like I'm curious what people are
doing towards this I want to be a breast
of it but I'm not like I'm in a totally
different category than people who are
like I'm actively working on this every
day so I've got a question around the I
think someone mentioned something about
I'm told you but I'm basically that the
distinction of of these shared purposes
and how I a shared purpose might be I'm
just like collectively understood maybe
a concrete way of saying it is if you
name something like climate change and I
name something climate change it's
entirely possible and probably like
we have very different ideas so what I
guess maybe like what can you say a bit
more about like how these addresses that
or have my yeah so in as much as I've in
as much as I've thought about that the
thought that I had basically went
something like you know in the same way
that people find themselves into like
fine you know there's a lot of different
climate change oriented groups on
Facebook say and so it's like what
causes you to be in one versus in
another and the answer to that might be
something like you know who else is in
it what kinds of conversations do they
have like how do they talk about this
topic how do they apparently understand
it and sort of who are the moderators of
it right and so I was kind of thinking
about like like there's currently a
thing where there's a thing where it's
like if you view if you view a purpose
that was created by somebody else rather
than you that instead of seeing settings
in the top right here you see something
like purpose holder and then like the
name of the person holding it so there's
a sense in which leg I was trying to
sort of as an initial stab at it to just
try to say okay who's a vision of this
purpose like who's articulation of what
we're trying to do here do i resonate
with and the idea that there could be
multiple different versions and i think
that yeah this is another thing that
could become quite unwieldy at scale and
another situation where it might make
sense to have something like you know a
list over here i don't if you guys can
sort of see my mouse but over here on
the left or something um actually can
you see my mouse yeah okay cool so list
somewhere over here that kind of you
know says something like related
purposes or something like that right so
people could kind of like you know these
purposes could kind of connect with each
other themselves but but ya know the
whole thing is an ontological nightmare
of course because like purposes and
goals and so on are not perfectly
hierarchical you know I might
goal half of which is totally related to
this purpose and half of which is
totally related to something else and
it's currently pretty hard to kind of
easily connect that here so that's
that's a design question that I'm
sitting with like when I launched this
with the effective altruists one of them
said well I've got this this goal like
half of it goes to ei coordination but
half of it is also related to this other
thing which isn't know so I don't know
how can you know do I link the goal or
not like how do I think about that and
that's that's something I don't have a
good answer for so that's I mean that's
another thing we could talk about today
but I currently have that under
questions we're probably not asking
because it's like there's not
necessarily a straightforward answer to
that given that it's an ontological
problem Jess should I ask some more
questions yeah maybe like one more or
something and then we'll have to move on
okay cool yeah so I kind of I'm gonna
actually maybe don't don't answer them
Malcolm I'm gonna ask some questions
that then in our breakout rooms we can
kind of like maybe make some some
progress towards so I noticed that in
your design there's no sense of really
being together with the people that are
in your that are in your shared purpose
right there's no presence even though
you have this Pomodoro working room kind
of thing that it does have a sense of
being together and there's not really a
way of vetting people except by maybe
sharing the link or not for me
you know hiring someone is like a way of
trying to create a shared purpose and
see how someone can do in a shared
purpose and see if you can really divide
up work within a shared purpose and this
is for me very difficult like I've often
made hires that later I was like oh gosh
this isn't working out or whatever and
so there's this whole space in between
just like working randomly under the
same shared purpose and like deciding
that you're a team which is kind of
I don't know ignored in your design so
far another area is feedback if I'm
making progress towards the goal
something that's that's kind of missing
is is whether other people are kind of
like noticing chiming in cheering me on
whether people respect what my sub goal
is as part of the you know do people
like like if I'm Elon Musk and I'm using
accomplice and I'm trying to work on
climate change and I ship electric cars
or whatever probably other people are
like oh yeah he's actually really
helping or at least some of them are but
you know if I'm if I'm somebody else
people might have a different opinion so
so there's like some question about
feedback and I feel like there's a whole
space of people finding each other
that's maybe not explored between just
sharing the link or making it public or
whatever like the question about how -
how would you actually want to find
people that that you would trust to be
pursuing a shared purpose together so I
just said it four things in like human
systems terminology I said time together
feedback loyalty or trust and
matchmaking are kind of like challenges
that I see here that might be worth
exploring and Jess do you want to say
what the plan is for the breakout rooms
yeah so Joe is gonna kind of drop some
very quick knowledge on a structure for
for the kind of discussions we're gonna
have in in breakout rooms but
essentially what we're gonna do is send
to our discussions around a couple of
questions and I think we're gonna shoe
inertia we scope that to the questions
we're asking today or I think maybe you
look at the doc again yes there's
questions we're asking today and then
there's these structural features that I
that I put in which include I will
highlight the ones that I just asked
about
I just got it hmm okay but they're also
kind of there in the dock like one of
them is there yeah yeah so we'll
highlight those and so maybe we
suggested in your breakout room you
discuss one of these questions either
under questions we're asking today or
structural features that might be
relevant so you can just take in your
group yeah and so then what we're gonna
do is well in in that bracket room we'll
discuss those things I invite you to get
at least one person to be writing down
thoughts or response if it come up from
your breakout group in in the section
that's called breakout groups and then
we're gonna join back in about ten
minutes and we're gonna have kind of a
more freeform discussion about that and
and present kind of any any thoughts or
feedback to Malcolm that that arose so
Jo do you want to explain the totals yes
this is just a way to have if you're in
a breakout room with like close friends
don't don't bother to do this but unless
you kind of don't trust them but if
you're in a breakout room with strangers
a good way to organize the discussion is
to talk in a funny way but I'll
demonstrate right now so if people have
a question they can make a like a turtle
II gesture like I am if you if you look
at my screen so this is like a kind of a
swimming tortoise something so if you
have a question like a curiosity you
make this shape if you have an idea you
make this shape this is like a rabbit
yeah if you have a clarifying question
or something that's like just a point of
order like we only have 30 seconds left
or something you make a kind of a fungus
rhizome kind of like little dance with
your fingers so there's these three ways
that you kind of like gesture as
starting your your contribution and the
the deal is that they the turtles rule
so like if you make this the people who
make the turtle thing the ideas are in
surface to them so this keeps us from
just like shouting out
our ideas and keeps us kind of like
focusing as a group on curiosity rather
than like oh my dear oh my dear oh my
dear
because the turtles are in charge of the
room so and if you have any questions
about that you can I think you should be
able to chat back at us from out from in
your your breakout room so if you're
like I'm lost or I don't understand then
then chat and myself or joke so we're
gonna start the breakout rooms now and
we'll be back in about ten minutes it
was good
our group is good okay cool well does
someone in there I want to give us a bit
of wisdom back what you all talked about
that's the question or something I'd be
happy to okay does that make sense yeah
is everybody back in yet uh I think
we're approaching most people being back
cool okay so yeah our group discussion
was really rich for such a short
discussion between people who didn't
know each other we explored a few
different directions
the main one was we looked at taking we
we looked at how to divide up people who
care about the same goal like climate
change or something like that in two
different theories of change so one idea
was to separate like have some
discussions sections underneath the
shared purpose like the climate change
shared purpose with some like why
discussion that we see thought would be
pretty easy and then somehow discussion
that would be very there would be a lot
of disagreements and we thought about
how people in the house section could
find people who have similar theories of
change or shared context so we talked
about like maybe they could find people
who agreed with same podcasts or social
theories or yes they could somehow like
aggregate around like
not only am i working on climate change
but I follow this social theory or at
this view
Michael Shellenberger or whatever you
know we also looked at so this started
to create a kind of a funny mix of a
social network that was about work and
also a social network that was more
about like different kinds of theories
and ideological positions on that work
which I thought was quite beautiful and
then we also talked very briefly about a
payments Network like a patreon model
where you support other people who are
working to the same for the same goals
yeah cool to someone from the Dussehra
Malcom James Nathan Tanya group that's
maybe not Malcolm want to just give like
maybe one question you were asking that
was particularly interesting or one kind
of consideration that you had that came
up one question you're asking is for all
of the different features this would
need to be like a whole organism like
does it want to have those inside it or
does it want to connect to something
outside an interface that has those
capabilities I guess like concretely
like it could link to a discord server
for instance like oh we talk over here
okay I'm just kind of jumping through
people because we have I showed amount
of time with the the Phil Dave Bulow of
the Brawn group does someone want to
kind of also offer a reflection and
maybe questions or something that you
were curious about during that time
you
one okay
I guess one of the well we had we had a
lot of interesting discussion and some
questions some of the questions that
popped up I wish we had more time to
discuss aviv mentioned this idea of like
tools versus actions phil was talking
about the the what versus the how and
the thing that i remember discussing at
the end was how a goal is kind of
amorphous and and could be really really
big and how at the very very bottom
there's just an individual with a single
intention or goal that might match and
if there was a tearing process and maybe
a goal holder like the SDGs actually has
people i don't know what they're called
exactly but they're like goal owners and
they kind of own a goal and they try to
make stuff happen around this particular
thing and it was just this idea of like
how is that tearing happening and how is
that coordinating happening why there's
like very very small actions and very
very huge i'd say like maybe there's
something called a vision like is there
any more levels that need to be created
okay um maybe Benjamin Nick Elliott and
starfish group if you want to if someone
wants to offer something from your your
group a question or a consideration
um something that starfish brought up
that I thought was really interesting
and it's interesting is that um the
accomplice seems like it could help with
like decentralized power in projects
where people are working together but
that they're too sort of different ways
so things can be decentralized either
there can be a core community with no
real leader but everybody is like
committed and working on the project and
the boundary is such that people don't
just pop in and out or there can be a
more open source style decentralized set
up where people are just able to drop in
and out as they please and there's no
centralized authority in that kind of
nature and I think most of our
discussion just centered around how
depending on which kinds of purposes you
had behind having shared purposes in the
first place you might use comp lists in
different ways
awesome and also if you guys have
comments on the notes of any other group
feel free to add like a comment in
Google Docs on there and you can kind of
continue that conversation so if you
have a response that you we don't have a
necessarily enough time to respond to in
person right now yeah you can add a
comment directly on there that groups
reflection in the doc so a 5-second yeah
something that came up that I kind of
thought would be interesting was it when
you have this kind of overall
overarching goals and be able to put in
an individual one if there may be a slot
but people who could put in where
there's gaps like I see this giant
project coming about and I see that
there's a lot of people are not easement
projects and say there's room for this
project but I once called it out maybe
kind of having an alert and then that
can match up if people who already have
that written down as one of their own
personal goals or people who want to
take on a new goal and they see this
huge project and I'd see a whole gap
here yeah cool thanks all right
and Sebastian Nicolas and Robin if
someone from that group wants to offer a
question or an inflexion this is the
moment where we would all stare at each
other if we could so I think I think
that I found really interesting was this
you took some time to kind of resolve
whether this is about working on
something together quite concretely or
about having a sense of like sharing the
same forest those people you can't see
because they walk in different paths of
it's different part of it and how that
might influence how you you would want
to design around the difference more
about like the sense of sharing
something or the actual practicality of
doing together anything else yeah we
also talked about kind of some of the
main issues that might come up are
similar to in other groups like how do
you have how do you for the people who
are in the group who do they bring in at
different times and how do they know
that you know
what's the trust network built around is
it built around shared goals is it built
around or you've I conceive you've done
actions about this already and I have so
so we could probably work is it built
around were were actually facing similar
problems we're in the same hometown I
think I I think I forget who it was but
some someone mentioned about you know
living in Scotland and the issue of
geothermal or oh sorry I'm like moving
to a Net Zero and if if you are also
facing or if you're also curious and
living in that same place and you could
do something about that maybe you could
work together so how could we offline
this from online to offline like how
does that move and then how do you have
enough difference in your group that
it's not just an echo chamber we didn't
really touch that one but that's always
gonna be kind of an issue with any group
that forms and so yeah
you
so we have a very short amount of times
I'm going to pasta Joe to wrap up rad I
mean I think we just sort of begun to
dive into a huge design space that's
that's that's really interesting
I think Malcolm maybe just with like
like from all the way up to all the way
down do you feel like this just like
helpful investigation I'm not sure I
could summarize it like with it with an
upper it down it has helped me think
about this a lot but it's one of those
situations where like you think you have
like something that's like almost done
and then you like think about it more
and then you're like oh my god there's
so much left to do
so so I feel less close to done than
when I came but that's not because I
have more completely less information or
something yeah I feel like I got a lot
out of this I'd love if people like
recorded their breakout groups which I
assume nobody did but like I would love
to just like listen to each of them and
be like why do people talk about um so
I'm just something like thinking about
that as part of the design of future
iterations of social design clubs or
something like that because it's like
yeah I'm looking at all these notes here
and some of them are just like the tip
of the iceberg of ideas that people have
and I'd love to dig in more if you guys
want to hit me up on Twitter at Malcolm
Ocean or I'm Malcolm underscore ocean
and just like share more thoughts of
thing about this you're welcome to do
that or whatever other media yeah I
think I'm I'm really interested in both
this being the beginning of like an
ongoing conversation with Malcolm like
opening a can of worms that we then kind
of like all explore asynchronously and
we can continue to use the Google Doc
it's like a coordination point for that
and also I move it in iterating and help
Jess and I do a better job next week I'm
not sure who will have but I think Edie
who's here will will present sometime
kind of soon Nathan Schneider there's a
bunch of great people who are interested
in presenting many of them here and I
also see a bunch of great human systems
people and yeah I'm excited about making
this this club work and we're
before the very end Joe that you do I
just want to give her a chance to give
us feedback because a bunch of people
have had ideas about the actual event so
I'm just going to post a feedback form
in the chat please help us out this is
the biggest gift you can give us right
now is feedback on the actual experience
of being at you then so yeah and the
last thing that I want to say is just I
think that we have kind of a huge task
ahead of us not just to redesign
accomplice but like all the other stuff
and and I would like to try to scale in
that direction so if you think of a
social design not necessarily something
that you're working on even but
something that's really frustrating for
you unemployment centers the DMV
Facebook voting in your town whatever
and you think about who would be the
ideal people to do that redesign with
and how can can you bring them here and
how can we like make this thing grow in
capacity so that we can help each other
do this stuff I think that's it thank
you all yeah thank you everyone for
coming
we do have a gift economy page if you
feel called to give a gift to the store
or facilitators but otherwise as I said
the biggest gift is giving us feedback
on this event and making it better and
coming back next week and telling the
cool social design is that you want to
be here yeah so thank you so much
everybody
it's been really great Cheers